Well, since we
are short on time,
I'll have to move on to
chapter five on property.
But explore when
you can what he says
about the state of war and
slavery in the Skip chapters.
We will also come back
to other subtleties,
like why he calls the
doctrine by everyone
in the state of nature
has executive power
this strange doctrine
in paragraph 13
and, for that
matter, why there is
no authority in the state of
nature besides each individual.
So what are his key
arguments on property?
Alyssa.
One is that each of us has a
property in our own person.
That's in paragraph 27.
Good.
And later in paragraph 27, that
we make things our property
by mixing our labor
with things from nature.
Very good.
Yeah.
I like the acorn example.
By picking up an
acorn, we make it ours.
I guess that applies
to fruit, too.
[LAUGHTER]
And he says in paragraph
26 that the Earth is ours
for the support and
comfort of our being
and that we're given
reason to use it well.
That brings me back to
my point from before.
Someone isn't using it
well if they're rich
and they hoard things.
Well, you can only
hoard so much.
Like, who needs 10 Ferraris?
I do.
Ha, ha.
Ha, ha, yourself.
The point is that you cannot
hoard because your things will
spoil.
Yes.
That is why he talks
about money somewhere.
Money doesn't go bad.
Yes, in paragraph 36.
But you'll see that he
says in paragraph 31
that everyone can take as
much as he wants from nature,
but there is a limitation.
What is that limitation that
prevents us from accumulating
so much that things spoil?
Well, what is also present
in nature besides things
you can take?
Oh, yes.
The law of reason.
It's stupid to hoard because
then you're just wasting stuff,
and that's against
the law of reason.
But once there is money, you
can hoard it without spoiling.
So why isn't that wrong to do?
Because you put
your labor into it?
But what if you're just lucky?
Or what if you inherited it?
OK if I answer this one?
It's because someone else
put their labor into it,
therefore they can give
however they choose.
Excellent.
Thanks.
Do you recall how much
Locke says labor increases
the value of what is in nature?
100 times in paragraph 40.
1,000 times in paragraph 43.
Both 10 and 100 times
in paragraph 37.
And since we mentioned
paragraph 40,
we should point out
his famous statement
in the subsequent one.
A king of a large and
fruitful territory in America
feeds, lodges, and is clad worse
than a day laborer in England.
So whatever the
factor of increase is,
the point is not just that
labor is almost all the value
in property but that
by protecting property
we will all benefit
with many good things.
Yes, like this university.
[CHUCKLES]
Exactly.
I still don't think it's fair
that some people have so much
more than others.
But we all benefit.
Besides, if it weren't
for this system,
you wouldn't even be able
to get that broken-down Kia
that you dream of.
Oh.
Ha, ha.
[LAUGHTER]
But even if the pie
gets bigger and bigger,
some people will
still control others
because they have
a bigger piece,
making those people unhappy.
Or do you mean less free?
If so, it seems that AI doesn't
solve the problem at all.
Of course, some people
do think that it can,
that mathematization
of all things
can lead to a sort
of techno utopia.
Locke is giving us a choice.
We can be controlled by
algorithms designed by smart
but unworldly people working
long hours in some basement--
or let's call it a cave--
or we can be allowed
our own choice.
Of course, that choice
should be the product
of thoughtful reflection,
particularly on our own biases.
But AI could give more
freedom, couldn't it?
I see what you're saying.
Certainly, it can bring
benefits in health care
and transportation and make
many things more efficient.
But intrinsically it
can't solve the problem
of bias even in itself.
Actually, it's even worse.
Those who develop and
therefore control AI
will build AI systems biased
for their own benefit.
Hmm.
Having said that, I
realized that we somehow
seem to have gotten
distracted from understanding
how natural right can help
us to address bias in AI.
And we only have a few
minutes of class left.
I was wondering when you
were going to realize that.
Well, you convinced
us that all AI systems
will be biased in
some dimensions
no matter what you do.
But then you also
convinced us that property
should be respected.
So, what do we do about bias?
Yeah.
And how should we
punish people who write
unacceptably biased AI systems?
Or reward them for making
acceptably biased AI systems.
I mean unbiased AI systems.
[LAUGHTER]
Yeah.
We can't reward
or punish people,
according to Locke's system.
On the contrary,
we can reward them
by buying their
products if we like them
or punish them by not
buying their products
if we don't like them.
So transparency is the key?
Yes, if people are willing
to pay for transparency.
You see, the law of
nature addresses that too.
And in most
contemporary approaches,
there is an
assumption, one which
we have been
addressing today too,
that bias is bad and
should be eradicated
by technical mathematical means.
We now understand that a deeper
reflection on the law of nature
and the law of reason is
needed, but we engineers
needed to see the limitations
of the mathematical or computer
science approach
first before we turn
to a broader or deeper one.
Yeah.
I think I understand
this now, but it still
hasn't changed one thing.
I want a Ferrari.
[SCOFFING, CHUCKLING]
The point is under the Lockean
system we are all better off--
happier, we could say--
because algorithms
with unacceptable
bias will go away because
no one will buy them.
You're starting to understand.